Welcome to Module 2: Node
Production Preparation. First of all,
how do you secure your app by using
environment variables? Environment
variables, they're great, great tools that
will allow you to prevent accidentally
publishing sensitive information, not use
GitHub, GitLab, or Gitbucket or any other
repository for your code, because they
might be hacked and they are hacked
periodically. You can check out the links
in the footnotes. Code is less flexible
when you actually hardcode some sensitive
information or some environment specific
information, such as the URL of your
database. Because if you are moving your
code from environment to environment,
that variable needs to change.
Let's take a look at this code example.
You might have done a similar coding and I
did too, especially on the earlier
stages when all I have is just one file.
Why bother? Well, obviously,
this code is not flexible at all.
If I want to move it from my development
environment to a QA, such as staging or
maybe CI/CD environment where I have
a different database, I should have a
different database at least,
and that code will be very inflexible.
I have to modify the value actually in the
code because I have my username,
"admin", and then I have the password
right there in the connection URL.
Same thing with API Key and API Secret.
It's not flexible at all and then as I've
mentioned, the version control systems,
they might be hacked or you might
accidentally publish it. So it's not a
good practice. Having a separate
config.json file or any json file,
it's not a good practice either.
It's a bad practice because most likely,
you still will be committing that file in
the code repository. So it's not any
different than having those variables in
a JavaScript file. Even Loopback, a very
popular framework, even that framework
uses datasources.json which is a bad
practice. The best practice is to use
environment variables. For example,
MY_ENV_VAR, all capitals with underscore,
has the value of "Hello". And then
within my Node.js code, I can use
process.env.MY_ENV_VAR. Similarly,
I can run the command on the next line.
In this case, in order for me
to save the environment variable,
I would need to say "export." This is just
a Linux standard command and please notice
that there's no spaces. There are no
spaces either before or after the equal
sign when you define the value for
environment variable. Now, more examples.
So going back to that piece of code where
we are connected to the database and
making our OAuth call, now we can
grab them from environment variables,
process.env.API_KEY,
process.env.API_SECRET,
and process.env.DATABASE_URL.
This way, it's very easy to transport
our code. Our code becomes very
flexible and portable. We can just
change the environment variable.
We don't have to modify the code itself.
And by the way, a lot of libraries support
NODE_ENV. When you set it to
"production," their behavior will change.
For example, Express, one of the
most popular Node.js frameworks,
has a different level of error messaging
and error stack tracing when you use it in
production. It has fewer because obviously
in production, you don't want to output a
lot of that information. It might expose
you, make your application more vulnerable
to attackers. Some of the ways to populate
environment variables or env vars.
First of all, we can populate them in AWS
EC2 user data. This is a specific place
where we initialize our environment,
either our cloud environment or our
application environment. So that's
a perfect place to set them up.
Also we could set env vars in Dockerfile.
AWS has a special mechanism for
provisioning infrastructure. It's called
CloudFormation, and we can set them up
right in the CloudFormation blueprint or
provide parameters, which when we create a
stack from the CloudFormation
blueprint, those parameters will be set.
Also, most of the cloud providers,
they have some type of a client,
a CLI client, Command Line Interface
client, and they would allow you to set
those environment variables, especially
platform as a service, such as Elastic
Beanstalk or Heroku. With the command
line, you can save any environment
variable for that particular app in a
cloud, so the value would be saved.